原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Alex  小食人魔 C_C Giggles  杨一勾
翻译：木浅  小僵僵   校对：木浅  某羽
时间轴：念念 吃土少女 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第十集
《诉讼双雄》
我想和你合作这个无偿案  掠夺性贷款
I want to work with you on the pro bono, predatory lending,
占有色人种的便宜
taking advantage of people of color.
我们有123个起诉人
We have 123 plaintiffs
被操控负担更高的贷款汇率
who were all steered into higher-rate mortgages.
他用你这样的傻瓜打掩护
And he's using fools like you to cover his own ass.
我绝不会在一个  有歧视的地方工作
I would never work for a place that engaged in discrimination,
而且我很乐意在法庭上这么说
and I more than happy to say that on the stand.
这个案子无关乎种族或钱
This case isn't about race or money.
掌管这家公司的人是个彻彻底底的掠夺者
The man who heads up this company is a predator,
25年前你姨妈为他工作过
and your aunt worked for him 25 years ago,
他把她的生活变成了地狱
made her life a living hell.
-因为她是黑人吗  -因为她是个美人
- Because she was black? - Because she was beautiful.
法官大人  我想提交这个文件
Your Honor, I would like to introduce this document.
除非他有文章提到的真实备忘录
Unless he has the actual memo it refers to,
否则这篇文章不能采纳
this article itself is inadmissible.
我想提交这篇文章的原因
The reason that I would like to have entered that article
是向法庭显示他把它毁了
is to show that he buried the memo.
-说谎  -不是说谎
- That is a lie. - It's not a lie.
我能证明
I can prove it.
他传唤我两日后出庭
He's calling me to the stand in two days.
我们得帮你准备好
Then we need to get you prepared
-还需要有观众  -模拟庭审吗
- in front of an audience. - A mock trial?
我不会让唐娜再遭受这种事
I'm not putting Donna through that.
首席检察官办公室给我发了传票
I've been subpoenaed by the Attorney General's Office.
你又要我进行人身攻击
You are asking me to go personal again.
我不干
And I won't do it.
我是在要你再保护我一次
I am asking you to protect me again.
而且你这么做不是坏事
And I am telling you it's okay to do it.
你后悔把哈维置于这个人之上吗
Do you regret putting Harvey over this guy?
我后悔把哈维置于我之上
I regret putting Harvey over myself.
另一条有什么不好
What was wrong with the other one?
什么
What?
这是你换上的第三条领带了
That's the third tie you've put on.
我就是不喜欢另外两条
Oh, I just didn't like how the other two looked.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
我从未见过你在庭审前对自己这么不自信
I've never known you to second- guess yourself before trial.
没事  我就是需要一条合适的领带
Nothing's going on. I just needed the right tie.
那会不会和这个人要找
Does that maybe have to do with this man
唐娜的麻烦有关
coming after Donna?
没有  是因为我得
No, just has to do with the fact
靠路易来准备我自己的案子
that I have to rely on Louis to prepare my own case.
你担心她也是正常的
It's okay that you're worried about her.
你生命中还有其他你在乎的女人
I don't feel threatened by you having another woman
不让我觉得受威胁
in your life that you care about.
事实上  你的忠诚是我一直
In fact, your loyalty is one of the things
欣赏你的地方之一
I've always admired about you.
-是吗  -当然
- It is? - Yeah, of course.
你关心的每一个人
You've felt betrayed at one time or another
都曾让你感到过遭受背叛
by almost every person you've ever cared about,
尽管如此
and in spite of that,
你还是在他们遭受威胁时保护他们
you protect them whenever they're threatened.
当然了  谁都会那么做
Of course I do. Anybody would.
不  不是谁都会  但你会
No, not anybody would, but you do,
所以唐娜和你生命中所有的其他人
and that's why Donna and all the other people in your life
能有你都是幸运的
are lucky to have you.
谢谢  宝拉
Thanks, Paula.
今天好运
Good luck today.
亚历克斯  不管你要去哪  调头
Alex, wherever you're going, turn around.
马利克传唤了唐娜  所有人都要帮忙
Malik subpoenaed Donna, so it's all hands on deck.
我是想帮忙  哈维
And I'd love to help, Harvey,
但我另有事要处理
but I need to get to another deck.
-怎么了  -布莱顿・古尔德
- What happened? - Bratton Gould happened.
我们不都解决掉他们了吗
I thought we took care of them.
我们是解决了布莱顿
We took care of Bratton,
现在另一个要来报仇了
and now the other one wants revenge.
-怎么说  -你觉得呢
- How? - How do you think?
-该死  辉瑞制药  -没错
- Shit, Pfizer. - Yup, Pfizer.
-需要帮忙吗  -哈维  如果我需要帮忙
- You need help? - Harvey, if I needed help,
我当初就拿不到辉瑞制药
I wouldn't have landed Pfizer in the first place.
亚历克斯
Alex.
拿下他们
Go get 'em.
二十五年前
我们已经读了42遍了
Well, that was the 42nd time we've read that.
-你改主意了吗  -没有
- Have you changed your mind? - Nope.
那男孩当初就不该叫
That boy was stupid for telling Elizabeth
伊丽莎白去
to go away in the first place.
-你们在看什么  -你觉得呢
- What are you two reading? - What do you think?
《伊丽莎白》
Ah, Elizabeth.
我们就是因为她才给你起了那个中间名
You know, we got the idea for your middle name from her.
才不是的
That's not true.
你确实很像她
Well, you are just like her
因为她也不许男人告诉她该做什么
because she doesn't let boys tell her what to do either.
而且她也跟她妈妈一样
And she's also just like her mother.
去那边看会儿书吧
Now, go read over there for a minute.
我想跟你姑姑说说话
I want to talk to your aunt.
-那姑娘真不一般  -是吧
- That girl is something else. - Don't I know it?
你单位那人怎么样了
What's going on with the guy at work?
你不用担心那个  罗伯
You don't need to worry about that, Robbie.
我能处理好
I can take care of it.
听我的
I'm telling you,
最好的处理办法
the best way to take care of it
就是悄悄调职
is to quietly get yourself transferred
别惹麻烦
and not make any trouble.
我不是那样的人
Well, that is not who I am,
如果你到现在还不知道...
and if you don't know that by now--
我知道
Yeah, I know, I know.
你  瑞秋  伊丽莎白  劳拉
You, Rachel, Elizabeth, and Laura, hell,
在这里丢只死猫
a man can't swing a dead cat around here
都会砸中个固执的女人
without hitting a strong-willed woman.
-打扰你了吗  -没有
- Am I interrupting? - No.
我就是在想案子
I was just thinking about the case.
我也是  我想我有办法
So was I, and I think I have a way
让案子不被撤销了
to keep it from getting dismissed.
说说吧
All right, let's hear it.
公司说他们有规程
The company says they have protocols in place
来避免歧视  但我们也知道
to prevent discrimination, but we also know
他们有个占女人便宜的执行总裁
that they have a CEO who takes advantage of women.
如果你是在说贾丝敏...
If you're talking about Jasmine--
我是说所有女人
I'm talking about women.
-什么意思  -我的意思是
- What's your point? - My point is, a man
能对贾丝敏姑姑做出那种事的男人
who did what he did to Aunt Jasmine
肯定也这样伤害过别的女人  那么...
has done this to other women, which means--
瑞秋  那不是歧视
Rachel, that's not discrimination.
-那是骚扰  -不  爸爸
- That's harassment. - No, Dad, it's treating
那是区别对待一群人
a group of people differently,
这就是歧视的定义
which is the definition of discrimination.
这容许我们抗辩有规律可循
And it sets the stage for us to argue a pattern.
看来我们得去找个
Then I guess we need to find someone
他也这么对待过的人了
he's done this to before.
就是这样
That's the thing.
我可能已经找到了
I think I already have.
时候到了吗  我五分钟后就到
Is it time? I'll be there in five minutes.
我需要点时间整理自己
I just need a second to gather myself.
随你吧
You can take all the time you need
我们不做模拟庭审了
because we're not doing this trial.
路易  你说什么呢
Louis, what the hell are you talking about?
马利克会在证人席上对我穷追猛打
Malik's gonna come after me on that stand,
你要为我做准备的
and you're supposed to get me ready.
我就是这意思
That's what I'm saying.
你根本不需要去作证
You're not gonna have to get up on that stand at all.
怎么了
What's going on here?
一图书馆的人都在等你们呢
We got a library full of people waiting for you two.
我正要过去
I was just about to come down there,
但路易告诉我
and now Louis is trying to tell me
我不需要我面对马利克了
that I don't have to go up against Malik.
路易  法官发传召令了
Louis, the judge issued a subpoena.
她必须作证
She's got to take the stand.
她不需要  你还不懂吗
No, she doesn't. Don't you see?
你曾在地检官办公室工作  而她是你的秘书
You worked in the DA's office. She was your secretary.
你们都办了克利福德・丹纳的案子
And you both worked on the Clifford Danner case.
我去  这是工作成果
Holy shit, it's work product.
这是受保密保护的  路易  你是个天才
It's covered under privilege. Louis, you're a genius.
我们去让图书馆的人走吧
Let's go clear out that library.
等等
Hold on a second.
进行模拟庭审就是为了让我做准备
The whole point of doing a mock trial is to prepare me.
万一这招不好使
What's the downside of still doing that
那么有备无患有什么坏处呢
in case this doesn't work?
坏处是  我就没有足够的时间
The downside is that I won't have enough time
为上庭准备辩据
to prepare the argument for court.
-我不懂  -哈维  我需要告诉你
- I don't see how that-- - Harvey, do I need to tell you
等我做完之后  要上庭用的人也不是你吗
that when I'm finished, you can't be the one to make it?
-不需要  -什么意思
- No, you don't. - Why not?
马利克是想拿这个案子针对我
Because Malik's trying to make this case about me,
所以要尽量让迈克开口
which means the more we can have Mike talk, the better.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
诉讼双雄
第七季 第十集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
怎么回事  他们人呢
Hey, what's going on? Where are they?
无所谓  模拟庭审取消了
It doesn't matter. The mock trial's off.
-取消是什么意思  -路易提出
- What do you mean it's off? - Louis came up
一个工作成果豁免论点
with a work product exemption argument.
唐娜压根不用出庭出证
Donna doesn't have to testify at all.
法官已经准许了吗
You got the judge to agree to that already?
他没批准  路易在想办法
He didn't agree. Louis is gonna work on it,
到时候你来做辩护
and you're gonna argue it,
所以你赶紧去办公室忙起来
so why don't you get down to his office and get busy?
哈维  这个计划很好  但是
Harvey, that's a great plan, but are you sure
你确定我们不做这事不是只是
we're not skipping this just to save Donna
为了不让唐娜在公司出糗吗
embarrassment in front of the firm?
不是  迈克  我们不做这个是要
No, Mike, we're skipping this thing to stop
阻止那混蛋在法庭上难为她
that asshole from going after her in open court.
这我知道  只是当你很在意某人时
I get that. It's just that when someone is special to you,
你的判断会...出现偏差
it can...mess up your judgment.
等我需要你对我的私生活发表意见时
And when I want your advice on my personal life,
我会告诉你  所以除非你觉得你处理不了
I'll ask for it, so unless you think you can't handle it
那我就得让路易去做...
and I have to tell Louis to do it--
我能处理好  哈维
I can handle it, Harvey.
那就赶快去路易办公室忙起来
Then walk yourself down to Louis' office and get ready
因为我们今天就要搞定这个混蛋
because we're shutting this son of a bitch down today.
你好  雪莉  他在吗
Hey, Shelley, is he in?
算了  我自己去瞧瞧
Never mind, I'll just go see for myself.
亚历克斯  等等  他和你有约吗
Alex, wait. Is he expecting you?
我可不想有
I sure as shit hope not.
你当真觉得我会让你
Did you really think I was gonna let you
把我的客户挖走吗
get away with poaching my client?
我没盘算什么  也没想挖人
I didn't think anything, and I'm not poaching anyone
因为我们有协议在先
because we signed an agreement not to touch
我绝不会想去碰你宝贵客户的
any of your precious clients with a 10-foot pole.
不  你只是碰巧要对我最大的客户
No, you just happened to manufacture a hostile takeover
进行恶意收购
of my biggest client.
我的客户做的任何决定
I have a legal obligation to assist my client
我都有法律义务予以协助
in whatever decisions they make,
如果这种义务碰巧让我不小心
and if that obligation happens to result in me
喝到了你的奶昔
drinking your milkshake,
只是附带的好处罢了
well, that's just a side benefit.
在你喝那杯奶昔时  等着被噎着吧
Well, while you're drinking that shake, choke on this.
我的客户要以不正当经销手段起诉你
My client is suing yours for unfair business practices,
联邦贸易委员会是不会让一家起诉
and there's no way the FTC lets a company suing their competitor
某对手的公司被该对手收购的
get acquired by that competitor.
这样的话  你最好再弄一份文件
In that case, you better be ready to file another one
因为这份文件在你回到你的
because this thing is gonna get tossed
小办公室前就会被扔掉
before you get back to your little office.
我准备好了  伊莱  我提醒你
I'm ready, Eli, and in case you forgot,
上次你们俩其中一个和我对着干
the last time one of you two went up against me,
他叫汤米・布莱顿
his name was Tommy Bratton,
不知道你注意到没  他已经不在这工作了
and I don't know if you noticed, he doesn't work here anymore.
起初  我试着一笑而过
At first, I tried to laugh it off,
但是亚瑟不停勾引我  所以我告诉他
but Arthur kept hitting on me, so I told him
我不感兴趣  让他停手
I wasn't interested and asked him to stop.
-他停手了吗  -不  他没有
- And did he? - No, he didn't.
最终  我没有得到他许诺的升职
Finally I didn't get a promotion that I'd been promised.
他说是因为我的绩效审核结果不好
He said it was because of poor performance reviews.
你的理解是
Which you understood to mean
你不肯和他上床
that you wouldn't sleep with him.
没错  当我如此质问他时
Yes. When I accused him of that,
他说如果我再提起这件事  他就解雇我
he said if I brought it up again, I would lose my job.
六周后  我还是被解雇了
Six weeks later, I was fired anyway.
亚瑟・基特里奇让我的生活一团糟
Arthur Kittredge made my life a living hell.
法官大人  控方传唤
Your Honor, the prosecution calls
唐娜・鲍尔森上庭
Donna Paulsen to the stand.
法官大人  我请求证人不得出席
Your Honor, I move to have that witness disallowed.
理由是什么
On what grounds?
理由就是他之所以要传唤证人
On the grounds that he's only calling the witness
是因为他另有所图
because he has a personal ax to grind.
法官大人  我们强烈否认这些指控
Your Honor, we vehemently deny these accusations,
但是这不重要
but it doesn't matter
因为他们所说的并不是歧视
because what they're claiming isn't discrimination.
因为她不肯和他上床  亚瑟・基特里奇
It turned into discrimination the second Arthur Kittredge
就没给她升职机会
passed her over for a promotion
这就是歧视
because she wouldn't sleep with him.
这既过分又惹人气愤
That's outrageous and inflammatory,
即使这是事实  这和公司如何决定
and even if it were true, what does any of it have to do
谁得到抵押贷款利率又有什么关系呢
with how a company determines who gets what mortgage rate?
我在试图向法庭解释
I'm trying to explain to the court
你传唤证人的证词需要保密的原因
why you'd call a witness whose testimony is privileged.
为什么要保密
How exactly is it privileged?
因为它是某个案子的工作成果  而且这是
Because it's work product, on a case, by the way,
哈维・斯佩克特而不是你名声在外的原因
that made Harvey Specter's name instead of yours,
现在你们想用它来诽谤他的名誉
and now you're trying to use it to smear his reputation.
法官大人  克利福德・丹纳和埃尔蒙特投资
Your Honor, Clifford Danner has nothing to do
一点关系都没有
with Elmont Investments.
唐娜・鲍尔森处理这个案子受到保密协议
Donna Paulsen's work on it is covered under privilege,
这整个案子现在就应该结束
and this entire case should be thrown out right now.
请原谅我的法式口音
And if you'll pardon my French,
这是我听到的最胡扯的话
that is the biggest load of bullshit I have ever heard.
你怎么想是你的事  律师
You can think whatever you want, Counselor,
但是加州第12巡回法庭不这么看
but the 12th Circuit in California felt differently.
法官大人  我们有先例  我们有证词
Your Honor, we have precedent. We have testimony.
-我们有犯罪模式  -斯诺思琪女士
- And we have a pattern. - Ms. Sonowski.
如果你们公司里有
If there is a culture of discrimination
歧视文化
within your company,
执行总裁有责任处理这种情况
the CEO is a reasonable person to ask about it.
24小时后对基特里奇先生进行取证
Mr. Kittredge will submit to a deposition in the next 24 hours.
法官大人  现在名声被
Your Honor, the only reputation
抹黑的人只有我
being smeared here is mine,
但更重要的是  我同意
but more importantly, I agree.
克利福德・丹纳和此案无关
Clifford Danner has nothing to do with this.
事实上  如果有类似的名字
In fact, if anything even remotely resembling
从我嘴里冒出
that name comes out of my mouth,
尽管告我藐视法庭  但如此同时
feel free to hold me in contempt, but in the meantime,
除非被告想提问
unless the defense would like to bring up
我三年级时午餐吃了什么
what I had for lunch in the third grade,
我得传唤我的证人了
I'd like to call my witness.
法官大人...
Your Honor--
保尔森女士  请上证人席
Ms. Paulsen, please take the stand.
保尔森女士  你在当法律秘书之前
Ms. Paulsen, could you please state your employment history
所从事的是什么职业
prior to becoming a legal secretary?
我是个演员
I was an actress.
你能靠演戏养活自己吗
And were you able to make a living at that?
不  我当服务员来增加收入
No, I worked as a waitress to supplement my income,
但我不知道这些事...
but I don't see what that has--
你现在收入多少  保尔森女士
And how much do you make now, Ms. Paulsen?
-六位数薪资  -没错
- Somewhere in the six figures? - Yes.
这和起保底工资加小费相比天差地别
That's quite an improvement on minimum wage plus tips,
-你说是不是  -我能怎么说
- wouldn't you say? - What can I say?
我现在工作做的很出色
I'm very good at what I do.
粉碎公司几年前接的
And was shredding a document related
科斯特尔汽车公司案的相关文件
to the Coastal Motors Case that your firm tried years ago
也是你所擅长的工作之一吗
one of the things that you were good at doing?
该死
Oh, shit.
他是怎么知道的
How the hell does he know about that?
不重要了  他已经知道了
Doesn't matter. He knows.
保尔森女士  我再问一次
Ms. Paulsen, I'll ask you again.
你是否销毁了那个案子的证据
Did you destroy evidence on that case?
我要提醒你你宣誓了
And I'll remind you that you're under oath.
反对  他提到的文件是假的
Objection. The document he's referring to was fake.
销毁虚假文件并不犯法
It's not illegal to get rid of fraudulent documents.
她毁掉证据时知道那是伪造的吗
Did she know that when she destroyed it?
这不重要  除非他打算因为
It doesn't matter, so unless he plans
证人做本职工作而起诉她...
to prosecute the witness for doing her job--
我的打算是询问证人
I plan to ask the witness questions.
希望我能有这个机会
I'd like the chance to do that.
-法官大人...  -斯佩克特先生  请安静
- Your Honor-- - Mr. Specter, back off.
由证人来回答问题
The witness will answer the question.
-是  我销毁了文件  -你的上司要你这样做
- Yes, I shredded the file. - At your boss' request.
-不  -鲍尔森女士  你是否
- No. - Ms. Paulsen, were you fired
在科斯特尔汽车一案期间被解雇
during the Coastal Motors trial
并在一周后恢复原职
and then rehired one week later?
-是  但是...  -此后
- Yes, but I-- - And since then,
你成为了事务所的首席运营官
you've become your firm's chief operating officer,
但你并不是律师出身  对吧
but you're not a lawyer, are you?
当首席运营官不需要律师出身
You don't need to be a lawyer to be a COO.
-你有工商管理硕士学位吧  -没有
- And do you have an MBA? - No, I don't.
当然没有
Of course you don't.
你只有戏剧学的学士学位
All you have is a bachelor's in theater,
你成为一名律师秘书之前
and you were a part-time waitress, part-time actress
是一名演员  还兼职做服务员
when you quit to become a legal secretary,
你一直在做这项工作  直到哈维・斯佩克特
which is what you were until Harvey Specter
一夜之间让你当上了首席运营官
made you COO overnight.
告诉我  你有这个职位通常所需要的
Tell me, do you have any of the qualifications
任何资格证书吗
normally required for that position?
我在这家事务所的时间比任何人都长
I have been at the firm longer than anyone.
我知道它是怎样运营的...
I know how it works--
我也知道  不过是
Oh, so do I, by breaking the law
让某些人犯点法  然后再奖励那些人
and then rewarding the people that do.
这是扯谎
That's a lie!
那你是怎样升职的
Well, then how did you get your promotion?
既然你不够格  我只想到了两种方法
Because there's only two ways I can think of
这两种方法可都拿不上台面
when you're not qualified, and they're both pretty distasteful.
反对  这是有意煽动
Objection! That's inflammatory.
请回答问题
Answer the question.
我来告诉你吧  是我自己要求升职的
I'll tell you how I got it. I asked for it.
是你要求的
You asked for it?
如果只是开口要求就可以
You know, if that's all it takes,
那我或许应该管斯佩克特先生要一匹小马
maybe I should ask Mr. Specter for a pony,
但我可不觉得有这么简单
except I don't think that's all it takes.
我觉得这需要你销毁证据  假装被解雇
I think it takes destroying evidence, getting fake fired,
然后再演一出戏  让一切圆满结束
and a little acting ability to pull it off.
-法官大人  他在自证  -那我就
- Your Honor, he's testifying! - Yeah, well,
到此为止了
then I'll wrap it up because
如果她在那件案子中愿意销毁证据
if she was willing to destroy evidence in that case,
她在这件案子中也会愿意
she's willing to do it in this one,
所以那篇文章里提到的备忘
and that is why the memo referred to
已经不见了
in that article no longer exists.
-法官大人...  -够了
- Your Honor-- - I've heard enough.
案子继续进行
This case is moving forward,
那篇文章可以被采纳为证据
and I'm allowing that article to be admitted as evidence.
贾丝敏  我跟你说过最好私下解决
Jasmine, I told you the best way to handle this was quietly.
而我跟你说过
And I told you that man
那个人道德败坏  活该接受取证
deserves to be exposed for what he is.
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
那你为什么不接我的案子
Then why won't you take my case?
因为人们活该怎么样和最后的结果
Because what people deserve and what they get
-不是一回事  -那个说过
- aren't the same thing. - And what happened
要永远保护我的大哥哪去了
to the big brother who said he'd always protect me?
我来告诉你怎么回事
I'll tell you what happened.
你说过这件事要按你的方式解决
You told him you were gonna handle this your way.
不  你不肯这样做是因为害怕
No. You won't do this because you're worried
得罪你在那家厉害的事务所里的老板
how it'll look to your bosses at that fancy law firm.
如果真是这样呢
So what if I am?
我拼命努力工作才进了哈佛法学院
I worked my whole life to get into Harvard Law,
那种地方是不会招你我这种人的
and then I got hired at the kind of place
但他们招了我
that doesn't hire people like you and me.
我挤进了一扇本该摔在我脸上的门
I got my toe in a door that's usually slammed in our faces,
但我要是像疯了一样接下这个案子
and if I take a case like this out the gate,
他们立刻就会让我走人
they'll let me go in a heartbeat.
或许吧  但如果你要我...
Maybe they will, but if you ask me--
我没有要你做什么  贾丝敏
I'm not asking you, Jasmine,
但你在要我为了一个不可能
but you're asking me to risk everything
赢的案子赌上一切
for a case that I can't win.
不  罗伯  我要你这样做
No, Robbie, I asked you to do this
是因为那个人毁了我的生活
because that man shattered my life,
我都不知道该怎么振作起来
and I don't know how I'm gonna pick myself up,
但我以为至少可以对簿公堂
but I thought at least I could do this
因为有你支持我
knowing that you had my back.
贾丝敏
Jasmine.
你就让自己顺顺当当进那扇门
You just make sure you get your foot
然后一路高升吧
all the way in that goddamn door.
-哈维  -我知道你要说什么
- Harvey. - I know what you're gonna say,
我们本该举行模拟庭审的
that we should have had the mock trial.
我不想听见这句话
Well, I don't want to hear it.
我没想这么说  哈维  我要说的是
I wasn't gonna say that, Harvey. I was gonna say
如果他再让她出庭作证
that if he puts her on the stand again
-面对同样一个陪审团...  -那就要看上去
- in front of that jury-- - It's gonna look even worse
-比刚才还糟  -詹妮...
- than it did just now? - Jenna--
你别想凭花言巧语逃避这件事
You're not gonna talk your way out of this.
上次我们在那儿的时候
The last time we were in there,
你说过等这一切结束  我们就赢了
you said when it was over, we'd win.
现在不仅赢不了  他还要用一份
Well, instead of us winning, he gets to use a memo
根本不存在的备忘录
that doesn't even exist.
不是不存在  是你根本没写
Not that doesn't exist, that you didn't write.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我觉得哈维说的是马利克对你公司的
I think what Harvey's saying is that Malik put the squeeze
某个人施加了压力
on someone in your company,
为了摆脱他  他们就去跟报社说
and to get him off their back, they went to the newspaper
你写过一份备忘
and said there was a memo that you wrote.
就算那是真的
Even if that's true,
你也永远别想找出是谁写的
you're never gonna find out who wrote it.
那就不从给报社提供信息的人入手
Then instead of starting with the person
我们jiu cong
who gave it to the paper,
接手了这个备忘录的人
we're gonna start with the person they gave it to.
-你好  路易  -别跟我说你好
- Louis, hey. - Don't "Hey" Me.
我想知道为什么我去大办公室
I want to know why I went down to the bullpen
却被告知我自己的律师没法接我的案子
and I was told by own associates that they can't get to my case
因为他们都在忙着给你干活
because every one of them is busy working for you.
因为伊莱・古尔德盯上辉瑞制药了
Because Eli Gould is coming after Pfizer.
糟了  那可是你最大的客户
Shit, that's your biggest client.
-我知道  -你什么时候发现的
- I know. - When'd you figure that out?
昨晚看到这个的时候
Last night when I saw this.
如果我没看错
If I'm reading this right,
在他们去找董事会之前  你还有36小时
you have about 36 hours till they go to the board.
是48小时  我今早提出了第一份诉讼
48. I filed my first suit this morning and gave Eli
让伊莱先跟联邦贸易委员会周旋一会儿
a song and dance about the FTC,
但他不傻  我这样做只能争取一点时间
but he's no fool, and all that does is buy us time.
你要多少律师就拿多少吧
Well, then you take all the associates you need,
因为我们要尽自己所能
'cause we're gonna do whatever it takes
保护委托人
to protect our client.
我们
We?
亚历克斯  我说过你就像家人一样
Alex, I told you, you're family,
我绝不会让
and there's no way I'm letting
伊莱亚斯・混蛋古尔德伤害我的家人
Elias Douchebag Gould hurt my family.
乔治・克拉克  我是迈克・罗斯
George Clark? I'm Mike Ross.
就是大卫那篇文章里的人
Oh, the guy David wrote that article about.
而我要以诽谤罪起诉你
And I'm the guy that's gonna sue you for defamation
除非你帮我们一把
unless you help us out.
为什么我要帮助
And why would I help someone out
威胁我的人
who's threatening me?
我不是威胁你  我是在跟你打包票
I'm not threatening. I'm promising.
因为你登载了一篇关于备忘录的报导
Because you ran a story about a memo
声称是我客户所写
that my client supposedly wrote
甚至不给她机会反驳
that you didn't even give her a chance to refute.
我不需要给她机会  我核实过
I didn't need to give her a chance; I had verification.
向谁核实
From who?
这就是你们的目的  想知道我的消息源
That's what this is about. You want my source.
你说对了
You're damn right we do.
我要是说了那在这行就再也混不下去了
And you know, I do that, and I'll never get another one.
等我们证明那便条是假的以后  你能给
And we prove that memo's fake, you'll be lucky getting a job
波托马克新闻报写影评就该谢天谢地了
doing movie reviews for "The Potomac News"
因为那报道不仅暗指我客户有罪
because that article doesn't just imply my client's guilty.
还暗指我包庇此事
It implies that I buried the damn thing.
鉴于消息源的高可信度  你八成包庇了
Well, considering the nature of my source, you probably did.
你刚说什么
What did you just say?
不是埃尔蒙特投资告诉我的
I didn't get it from Elmont Investments.
而是认识你的人告诉我的
I got it from somebody who knows you.
-胡说  不可能  -是认识他的人还是同事
- Bullshit. That's not possible. - Knows him or works with him?
给我消息的人
The person who gave it to me
曾和你们是同事
had a working relationship with both of you.
依我来看  这便是实证
As far as I'm concerned, that's verification,
如果你们还觉得不够的话
and if that's not good enough for you,
那请立刻起诉我
then you go ahead and sue me
我要说的就这么多
because that's all I'm gonna say.
你来了  外卖呢
There you are. Where's the food?
我想我们可以出去吃
I was thinking we could go out to dinner
休息会儿再工作
instead of working through.
不  瑞秋  我们只有一次机会
No. Rachel, we only get one shot at this.
我们得做好充分准备  不能离开
We need to be ready. We can't go out.
我们正在准备取证
We're preparing for this deposition.
如果我说我们根本
And what if I told you that we don't have to do
不必取证呢
a deposition at all?
和解条款  你在开什么玩笑
A settlement offer? You got to be kidding me.
爸  这些条款还算合情合理
Dad, the terms are good.
我不在乎
I don't care how good they are.
只要我和那混蛋面谈  这些条款会更合理
Once I get that bastard in the room, they're gonna get better,
而他们却只和你接触谈论和解
and they only came to you with this
是因为他们深知我根本不屑一顾
because they knew I'd tell them to kiss my ass.
不是他们来找我协商  而是我找他们
Except they didn't come to me. I went to them.
什么  你竟敢出卖我
What? You goddamn undercut me?
我没有出卖你  而是去谈一桩交易
I didn't undercut you. I negotiated a deal
因为我很担心
because I am worried
你去面谈后会发生不好的事
about what'll happen if you get in that room.
你刚对我说什么
What did you just say to me?
你甚至无法和信贷员保持团结协作
You couldn't keep it together with a loan officer.
那要是你和曾伤害过你妹妹的人面对面
How's it gonna go when you're face-to-face
到时会变成怎样的局面
with the man that hurt your sister?
我来告诉你  我会让他乖乖招供
I'll tell you how. I'm gonna crack that man wide open.
亦或是你一败涂地导致我们最终一无所得
Or you'll lose your shit and we'll get nothing.
你都不知道你在说什么
Oh, you don't know what you're talking about.
爸  我曾说服某个人去冒一次风险
Dad, I once convinced a man to put his life on the line
而不是接受条款  因为我相信我们会赢
instead of taking an offer because I believed we could win,
而我现在要告诉你  我不认为我们能赢
and I'm telling you, I don't think we can.
瑞秋  我曾选择当一名懦夫
Rachel, I took the coward's way out once before.
我不能重蹈覆辙  我宁可拼一下
I can't do it again, and I'd rather take my shot
也不愿畏而却步  至少虽败犹荣
and go down swinging than walk away from the ring.
好吧
Okay.
那就按你说的办
Then we'll do it your way.
但有一个条件
But on one condition.
险中求胜的人不是你
You're not taking the shot.
得是我
I am.
唐娜  庭上的事顺利吗
Donna, hey, how'd it go in court?
我本应早点问  但我有一堆文档要审查
I would have asked you earlier, but I had a ton of doc review.
路易  我现在真的不想谈这件事
I really don't want to talk about it right now, Louis.
好吧  发生了什么
Okay. What happened?
很明显有什么地方不对劲
Because obviously something's wrong,
我是你的朋友  我随时愿意帮你
and I'm your friend, so I'm here for you.
-去你的愿意帮我  -什么
- Bullshit you're here for me. - What?
-我曾让你保护我  但你只保护了自己
- I asked you to protect me, but all you did was protect yourself
因为你不想问那些
because you didn't want to ask me
马利克问我的问题
the same kinds of questions that Malik did.
马利克问你的问题是什么意思
What do you mean that Malik did?
迈克需要做的只不过是...
All Mike needed to do was--
他没有问我克利福德・沃特金斯的事
He didn't ask me about Clifford Danner.
而是问科斯特尔汽车公司
He asked me about Coastal Motors.
-天呐  那便条  -对  便条
- Oh, my God, the memo. - Yeah, the memo.
然后他让我出庭作证
And then he put me on that stand,
对我步步紧逼  就像我害怕他如此似的
and he came after me just like I was afraid he would.
唐娜  谁也无法预料到事情会如此发展
Donna, there was no way we could have seen that coming.
我们所能预料的只是  如果他让我作证
What we could have seen coming was, if he got me up there,
他就会扭曲事实  含沙射影编造丑事
he would twist the facts, and he would imply ugly things.
-关于你和哈维  -对  关于我和他
- About you and Harvey? - Yes, about me and Harvey,
总是关于我和哈维
'cause it's always about me and Harvey.
上回是  这回也是...
Last time, this time--
-唐娜...  -去你的  路易
- Donna-- - God damn it, Louis,
我求了你帮我
I begged you to help me.
我还问过  如果你的计划行不通怎么办
I even asked, "What if your plan doesn't work?"
但你没听进去以致马利克问得我惊慌失措
but you didn't listen, so Malik rattled me,
他还羞辱我
and he humiliated me.
他说我是在一夜之间
And he said I am only COO
摇身一变成为首席运营官
because I slept my way there,
还说得有模有样
and he made it sound plausible,
因为你  现在这些都被记录在案
so now that's on the record thanks to you.
我  哈维和我一样是同意这计划的
Me? Harvey signed off on this just as much as I did.
我不管哈维做了什么  路易
I really don't care what Harvey did, Louis,
因为我是求你帮忙  你却让我深陷困境
because I came to you for help, and you left me high and dry.
路易  抱歉
Louis, forgive me,
但我不懂你为什么这么生气
but I don't understand what you're so upset about.
我生气是因为唐娜怒斥我
I'm upset because Donna laid into me
就像整件事都是我的错似的
like the whole thing was my fault.
路易  难道你不明白她只是在发泄吗
Louis, don't you see she was just venting?
我不管
I don't care.
我提供了十分安全的方法来防止她出庭
I gave them a foolproof way to get her out of testifying
是他们搞砸的  不是我
and they dropped the ball, not me.
如果真的是这样  那这事
If that's true, this shouldn't be
理应无法对你产生这么大的影响
affecting you so much.
所有这事肯定有原因
So there has to be an explanation
你之所以这么生气
as to why you're so upset,
也许是因为你没有如你保证般
and perhaps it has to do with you not going through
完成这模拟审判
with the mock trial like you promised you would.
这是关于她的  不是我
This is about her, not me.
你不觉得当你对自身感到羞愧时
You don't think that questioning someone
询问别人的亲密关系
about their intimate relations
可能会让你大动肝火吗
when you're feeling shame about your own might touch a nerve?
我不信
I don't believe this.
你是指这和希拉有关
You're saying this is about Sheila?
我是说可能
I'm positing it might be.
那我得说让我大动肝火的是
Well, I'm positing what touches a nerve
我本是来寻求帮助的
is that I come to you for help,
你却说这全是我的错
and you're saying this is all my fault.
我并没有这么说  路易
I'm not saying it's your fault, Louis,
我试着在帮你
and I'm trying to help you.
胡说
Bullshit.
路易  你知道我会尽可能地帮你
Louis, you know I would do anything I could to help you.
你不会  与其等你告诉我剩下的
Well, you're not, and instead of waiting for you
会谈时间不多了
to tell me that my time is up,
我准备现在开始保护自己
I'm gonna go ahead and protect myself
离开这个鬼地方
and get the hell out of here.
如果他们认识我们  那范围就能缩小了
Okay, if they know us, that narrows it down.
对  缩小到一千人至两千人左右
Yeah, to 1,000 or 2,000 people.
这一两千人并不全都在我们手下工作过
1,000 or 2,000 people didn't used to work for us.
这根本说不通
You know what? This doesn't make any sense.
我们一周前才开始处理这个案子
We've just had this case for a week.
如此说来  那个人现在就在这里工作
By that logic, it would have to be someone who works here now.
也可能是时不时在这里工作的人
Or it could be someone who works here from time to time.
你是指谁  唐娜
What are you getting at, Donna?
我指霍莉・科伦维尔
I'm getting at Holly Cromwell.
他为什么会去找霍莉
Why would he go to Holly?
因为那个记者会相信她能拿到东西
Because that reporter would believe that she has access.
如果马利克想找人
If Malik needed to enlist someone to do
做这种事  谁更合适
something like this, who better to do it?
而且最重要的是  她对我们都没好感
And on top of that, she has no love for any of us.
如果这是真的  马利克就从
If what you're saying is true, Malik just went from
胁迫别人变成了伪造证据
strong-arming someone to fabricating evidence.
不  他没有
No, he didn't.
我的天  这家伙真厉害
Jesus Christ, this guy's good.
这是什么意思
What are you saying?
他只是给了记者一个故事
All he did was give a story to a reporter.
这不叫伪造证据
That's--that's not fabricating evidence.
这甚至算不上犯罪
That's not even a crime.
他知道那是伪造的  而在庭审上承认了
Well, he admitted it at trial knowing it was false,
这当然是犯罪
and that sure as hell is.
哈维  他什么都没承认
Harvey, he didn't admit anything.
是我们承认了  因为他设套让我们这么做
We did, because he baited us into doing it.
他举起报纸装作要开始陈述
He held up the newspaper as if he was about to enter it,
但随后他说"文件"
but then he said "Document"
另一只手又举起了一份材料
and held up a folder with the other hand.
唐娜  我们需要一份文录
Donna, we need a transcript
确保迈克说的是真的
to make sure what Mike's saying is true.
我不需要文录  哈维
I don't need a transcript, Harvey.
我在脑子里都记下来了
I've got it all right here.
我告诉你  文章里提到了你
I'm telling you, you entered that article.
这或许不是犯罪
Well, it may not be a crime,
但如果霍莉站出来  他就会败露
but if Holly comes forward, he's gonna lose,
意味着我得马上去找霍莉
which means I'm going over there right now.
-不  哈维  我去找她  -唐娜  最初
- No, Harvey, I am. - Donna, you were the one
就是你当面拒绝她来这里工作
who made her refuse to come here in the first place.
她绝不会听你的
She'll never listen to you.
哈维  那个混蛋羞辱我
Harvey, that son of a bitch humiliated me
告诉世界我不配身居高位
and told the world I don't deserve my job.
我不只要证明他错了
I don't want to just prove him wrong.
我要让他后悔遇见了我
I want to make him regret he ever met me.
-准备好进行取证了吗  -随时准备着
- Ready for your deposition? - As ready as I'll ever be.
这计划很棒  瑞秋  会成功的
It's a good plan, Rachel. It should work.
你想跟我一起走吗
Do you want to head up there with me?
我可以载你一程
I can drop you off on the way.
不  你去吧
No, no, you go ahead.
去之前我有些事情要处理
I got something I want to take care of before I head in.
马利克的案子吗
Malik case?
事实上  是宝拉・阿加德
Actually, Paula Agard.
她在半个小时前打过电话来
Yeah, she called about a half hour ago.
她想送哈维特别的礼物
She wants to get Harvey something special,
问我有没有什么主意
wanted to know if I had any ideas.
-她为什么打电话给你  -我不知道
- Why did she call you? - I don't know.
我猜或许她认为我是哈维最好的朋友
I guess maybe she thinks that I'm Harvey's best friend.
也或许因为最了解哈维的那个人
Or maybe because the person that knows Harvey the best
是她唯一绝不会通话的人
is the only person she'll never call.
好吧  你在想什么
Okay. Got something on your mind?
唐娜有一天晚上来这里
It's just, Donna was here the other night,
告诉我多年以前有过一个人
and she told me about this guy from years ago and...
但她选择了哈维而不是他
she chose Harvey over him,
我问她是否后悔  然后...
and I asked her if she regretted it, and--
-然后什么  -这让我在想
- And what? - I guess it just made me wonder
真正让她后悔的是不是
if what she really regrets
她从未告诉哈维她的感受
is never telling Harvey how she feels.
无论如何  我得走了
Anyway, I've got to get going.
-路易  我们有麻烦了  -这次又是什么
- Louis, we have a problem. - What is it now?
我使劲浑身解数对付古尔德  全都落空了
I threw everything in the book at Gould. None of it worked.
更糟糕的是  他们还加快了行动速度
On top of that, they just moved up the timeline.
那你需要联系董事会
Then you're gonna need to contact the board
提议法人调整
about a corporate amendment.
路易  我是说我们想尽了一切办法
Louis, I'm telling you we've looked at everything:
绝对多数制  金色降落伞  毒丸计划
supermajority, golden parachute, poison pill.
"皇冠之珠"的办法怎么样
What about the crown jewels?
你深入他们的各个部门
You go through their divisions,
找出最脆弱的那一个
and you find the one that's most valuable.
我懂"皇冠之珠"防御策略是怎么回事  路易
I know what the crown jewel defense is, Louis.
问题在于  即使我能找到买家同意条款
The problem is, even if I could find a buyer and agree to terms,
我们也赶不及完成此事
there's no way we could push it through in time.
等等  我们不需要赶着完成
Wait a second. We don't need to push it through in time.
我们只用让他们以为我们完成了
We just need to make them think we did.
你疯了吗  纸包不住火
Are you crazy? A bluff is never gonna work.
他们认识全国所有的合法买家
They know every legitimate buyer in the country.
我没说要找合法买家
I am not talking about a legitimate buyer,
也当然不是说要找
and I am definitely not talking about them
美国的买家
being from this country.
-你来这里干嘛  -我来是为了
- What are you doing here? - I'm here to apologize
我俩上次见面发生的事向你道歉
for what happened the last time we met.
你来是因为有所诉求
You're here because you want something.
你说得对  但请听我说完
You're right. I do, but please just hear what I have to say.
你有三十秒时间
You have 30 seconds.
你告诉我你找到引人注目的东西
You told me that you find out what makes people tick
然后利用它来得到自己想要的
and you use that to get what you want
这能奏效是因为人们无视大局
and it works because people don't see the bigger picture.
-没错  -你没告诉我的是
- That's right. - What you didn't tell me
你学到这招
was that you learned how to do that
是因为你的继父是个酒鬼
because your stepfather's an alcoholic,
所以你学会读懂人心
so you learned to read people
成为他们想让你成为的人  以保护自己
and be who they want you to be to protect yourself.
这不是用来评判你的理由
That's not something to judge you for.
好吧  我接受你的道歉
Okay. I accept your apology,
但我不能做你请求的事
but I can't do what you're here to ask.
他手里有你的把柄  对吗
He has something on you, doesn't he?
我的人生并非一清二白  唐娜
I haven't exactly led a crime-free life, Donna.
所以  请原谅我...
Now, if you will excuse me--
不管他有你什么把柄  我们都能为你辩护
We can defend you against anything he has on you.
我不能冒这个险  因为鉴于你刚才承认
I can't risk that. Because given the history
曾用来评判我的这段黑历史
you just admitted you judged me for,
如果我所面对的陪审团里有个女人相信这个
if I ever stand in front of a jury with women on it--
霍莉  拜托  我们需要你帮忙
Holly, please. We need this.
对不起  唐娜
I'm sorry, Donna.
如果我能帮你肯定帮  但我办不到
If I could help you, I would, but I can't.
基特里奇先生  贵公司90%的高管都是男性
Mr. Kittredge, 90% of your executives are male.
-对吗  -我不知道
- Is that correct? - I wouldn't know.
我以工作表现来评估员工
I evaluate my employees
而不是性别
based on their work and not their gender.
那他们的肤色呢
And what about the color of their skin?
我想你和丽莎・戴维斯见过面了
I believe you had a meeting with Lisa Davies.
她是我们的高级信贷员之一
She's one of our senior loan officers.
你是说你委派以掩盖自己罪行的那个有色女人吗
You mean the woman of color you sent in to hide your crime?
这怎么回事  我以为我到这里
What is this? I thought I was here
回答一些关于贷款流程的问题
to answer some questions about our loan process.
我会问的  但首先我想
And I'll get to that, but first I would like
问你关于艾丽西娅・泰勒的事
to ask you about Alicia Taylor.
-谁  -因为她不跟你上床
- Who? - The woman that you fired
而被你解雇的那个女人
because she wouldn't sleep with you.
你确实这样做过  对吗
You did do that, didn't you?
艾丽西娅・泰勒与本案无关
Alicia Taylor has no bearing on this case.
她是本案的问题所在
She's everything that's wrong with this case.
抱歉  你有什么要问的吗
I'm sorry. Is there a question?
是的
Yes.
迷人女性们会吓到你吗  亚瑟
Do attractive women intimidate you, Arthur?
不  这怎么会
No, why would they?
因为她们坚强又强势
Because they're strong and they're powerful
知道自己想要什么
and they know what they want.
我对女性员工或其他员工都一视同仁
I value my female employees like anyone,
你也没证据反驳
and you have no proof otherwise.
那请回答我的问题或者引用第五修正案
Then answer the question or take the fifth.
你是否曾试图和某人上床
Have you ever tried to sleep with someone
然后她们要是拒绝你  你就报复
and then retaliated once they rejected you?
答案是不  我没有
The answer is no. I haven't.
当然对于不是我手下的女人  情况也不一样
Of course, things are different for women who don't work for me.
比如我马上就会约你
I'd ask you out in a second.
-你注意点  -爸  我搞的定
- Watch yourself. - Dad, I've got this.
没关系的  我知道他是谁
It's all right. I know where he's coming from.
毕竟  他是你爸爸  人也不瞎
I mean, after all, he's your father, but he's not blind.
他知道你有多迷人
I mean, he knows you're attractive.
-阿瑟  -其实
- Arthur. - As a matter of fact,
要我说了算  我很乐意
if it were up to me, I'd be willing
先约一发  也可能两发
to settle this for one date, maybe two.
好了  够了
All right, that's enough.
这就是讽刺之处
You see, that is the irony here.
你们控告我歧视
I am being accused of discriminating
有色人种
against people of color
但其实我更喜欢有色女性
when in fact I have always preferred women of color.
就是喜欢他们这种
There's just something about them.
异域风情
You know, they're exotic.
-就像你一样  赞恩小姐  -你个混蛋
- Like you, Ms. Zane-- - You son of a bitch,
我要确保身败名裂的人是你
I'm gonna make sure you're the one that loses everything
而不是那些你觊觎的人
and not the people that you prey upon.
-爸  -像你妹妹那样的吗
- Dad. - You mean people like your sister?
-说的就是她  -爸
- You're goddamn right I do! - Dad.
我妹妹是我的一切  而你抹杀了她的光亮
My sister meant everything to me, and you stole her light,
如果我最后只能做一件事
and I'm gonna make sure that you pay for it
那一定是让你为此付出代价
if it's the last thing I do.
那我怕这起诉讼你是办不到了
Well, I'm afraid it's not gonna be with this suit
因为你刚承认了
because you just admitted it's nothing more
这根本就是一场蓄意报复  我们也录音了
than a trumped-up vendetta, and we have it on record.
我花了好一会儿才记起来的  不过一旦想起了
Took me a while to remember, but once I did,
我就知道该怎么治你了
I knew exactly how to take care of you.
她说什么
What did she say?
说她就是信息源
That she was the source.
让我猜猜  但她不肯出庭作证
But let me guess, she won't testify.
她不肯  但我会的
No, she won't, but I will.
唐娜
Donna--
她承认了他联系过她
She admitted that he contacted her.
你说过这就是我们需要的
That's what you said we needed.
我说我需要她去说  不是你
I said I needed her to say it, not you.
为什么不能是我
Well, why can't it be me?
我的话和她的一样
My word is as good as hers.
-那不重要  -为什么
- It doesn't matter. - Why not?
因为在目前的情况下  不一样
Because in this situation, it isn't.
你是指他搞的好像
You mean the situation where he made it look like
我什么都肯为你做因为我...
I would do anything for you because I--
我不管他搞成什么样子
I don't care what he made it look like.
都不是真的
It's not true.
我非常非常想报复回去
I wanted to get back at him so badly.
而且也希望是由我来动手
And I wanted to be the one to do it.
-确实是由你来动的手  -怎么说
- You were the one to do it. - How?
你想到了是霍莉  但事实是
You realized it was Holly, and the truth is,
不管谁开口  她都不会答应的
she was never gonna say yes no matter who asked.
那我们怎么办
So what are we gonna do?
迈克和我要用你给我们的东西
Mike and I are gonna use what you gave us
给安德鲁・马利克点苦头吃吃
to put a gun to Andrew Malik's head,
如果我们用对了的话
and if we do it right,
他会后悔见到你
he is gonna regret the day he met you.
好的  我早上再打给你  妈妈
Okay, I'll call you in the morning, Mom.
多少睡一会儿
Try to get some sleep.
罗伯特  发生什么了
Robert, what's wrong?
贾丝敏两个小时前去世了
Jasmine died two hours ago.
罗伯特  真遗憾
Oh, Robert, I'm so sorry.
我本来可以帮她的
I could have helped her.
我应该帮她的
I should have helped her.
-别  别这样对自己  -对自己怎样
- No, don't do that to yourself. - Do what?
面对现实吗
Face the truth?
那个人毁了她的一生  我却袖手旁观
That man ruined her life, and I did nothing.
过去的两年  你已经在尽全力
You were there for her in every way possible
帮助她陪伴她了
for the last two years.
她也不是因为那件事而死的  她是病死的
She didn't die from that. She died 'cause she got sick.
但她求我那次我没答应
But I wasn't there the one time she had asked,
如果我答应了
and maybe if I was--
我做完作业啦
I finished my homework!
爸爸  你还好吗
Daddy, are you okay?
爸爸听到了坏消息  甜心
Daddy got some bad news, sweetheart,
我们让他自己静一静
so why don't we give him a minute?
我看你一直在想事情
I keep catching you lost in thought.
我一直在想这件案子
I keep thinking about this goddamn case.
我也是
So was I.
希望你想到了点什么
Well, I hope you got something
因为我就像你担心的那样
'cause I really shit the bed in there,
搞砸了
just like you were afraid I would.
爸
Dad--
我们应该接受那个提议的  瑞秋
We should have taken that deal, Rachel.
你是对的
You were right.
也可能不是
Maybe not.
事实上  可能你还是应该
In fact, maybe you should have that one-on-one
和基特里奇单独谈谈的
with Kittredge after all.
你的意思是
What are you getting at?
我在想  他利用你的弱点来攻我们
I was thinking he used your weakness against us,
那我们为什么不用他的弱点去攻他呢
so why don't we use his weakness against him?
我们对那个取证  不就是这个意思吗
Isn't that what we tried to do with that deposition?
就像你以前周末吼电视的时候那样
Yeah, but like you used to yell at the TV on Sundays,
如果正面对抗行不通
if running it up the middle isn't working,
那就帮大家个忙  去做长传吧
then do us all a goddamn favor and call an end-around.
那些比赛你还真是认真听了啊
You were really listening to all those games, weren't you?
不是比赛  爸爸
Not the games, Dad.
我听的是你说的那些话
I was listening to you.
迈克  你来干什么
Mike, what are you doing here?
我以为你和哈维要去见马利克
I thought you and Harvey were going to see Malik.
是的  不过要在一小时后
We are, just not for another hour.
只是想和你聊聊
Just wanted to talk to you about-
说什么
What is it?
唐娜  瑞秋告诉我
Donna, Rachel told me
我因为洛根・桑德斯的事搬出去的时候
that when I moved out because of Logan Sanders,
是你告诉她要给我点空间
you told her to give me some space
因为车到山前必有路
because things work out the way that they're supposed to.
-但她没有  -这就是我要说的
- But she didn't do that. - Well, that's my point.
迈克  你带着这个要去哪里
Mike, where are you going with this?
去告诉哈维你是怎么想的
Tell Harvey how you feel.
什么
What?
我知道我没有立场说这些  但是唐娜
I know that it's not my place to say this, but, Donna,
如果不是你  我不会和瑞秋在一起
I wouldn't be with Rachel if it wasn't for you,
如果我让你丢了某样东西  让你不能
and if I let you lose something that might make you
和我们一样开心
as happy as we are
而我还无动于衷的话  我永远不会原谅自己
and I didn't say something, I would never forgive myself.
所以如果你觉得  哪怕有一丝可能
So if you think there is even the smallest chance
你有想过要和他在一起
that you might ever want to be together
但你又没有那么快告诉他
and you don't tell him that soon,
那你可能就再也开不了这个口了
you might lose the chance to tell him at all.
迈克...
Mike...
我感谢你的一番心意
I appreciate where your heart is,
但两个人在一起要两厢情愿才能开心
but two people have to want to be together to be happy,
而哈维和我不想在一起
and Harvey and I don't want to be together.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
-你想让我怎么做  -你之前说过
- You want me to do what? - You said before that
只要你力所能及就都会帮我
you would do anything in your power to help me.
现在我开口了
Well, now I'm asking.
路易  我是说在这间办公室里  你明知道
Louis, I meant in this office, and you know it.
你叫我假扮成别人
You're asking me to pretend to be someone I'm not,
这超越了我的执照权限
which is a violation of my license.
蒙利诉玛洛湾案不是这么说的
Not according to Munley v. Marowan, it's not.
我不知道这是什么
I don't know what that is.
因为你是一个心理医生而不是律师
Well, that's 'cause you're a psychiatrist and not a lawyer,
但是我需要你假装
but what I need you to be
一名德国制药公司代表
is the head of a German pharmaceutical company.
-路易  -斯坦  拜托
- Louis!  - Stan, please.
我已经让唐娜失望了
I already let Donna down,
而我又无法弥补
and I can't do anything to help that,
如果我一天两次让我在乎的人失望
and if I let someone down that I care about twice in two days,
我算什么合伙人
what kind of partner am I?
更重要的是  我算什么朋友
More importantly, what kind of friend?
路易  抱歉
Louis, I'm sorry.
不管是否超越我执照权限
Violation of my license or not,
你的要求不合职业道德
what you're asking me to do is unethical,
我不会做
and I won't do it.
怎样
Well?
抱歉  亚历克斯  他拒绝了
I'm sorry, Alex. He said no.
你们是来和解的吗
Well, did you come to cut a deal?
只要包含你认输我获胜
'Cause I'm all ears as long as it includes
我就洗耳恭听
an admission that you lost and I won.
我们来讨论坦白的
Oh, we're here to talk about an admission,
但不是你想的那样
but not the kind you think.
我们来讨论你坦白
Yeah, we're here to discuss an admission
在法庭捏造证据
of fabricated evidence into court by you.
我不知道你们在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我没做过
I did no such thing.
我们知道你没做
We know you didn't do it yourself.
你让两个傻瓜帮你做的
You had two idiots do it for you.
如果你这么承认的话  哈维
If it's all the same to you, Harvey,
实际上我不认为自己是傻瓜
I actually don't consider myself an idiot.
有道理  你是想出来他诱导我们
Ah, you have a point. You were the one who figured out
为他带进来报纸的那个
he baited us into entering that newspaper for him.
但说实话  是唐娜想明白
But, to be fair, though, it was Donna who figured out
他找了霍莉・科伦维尔
that he went to Holly Cromwell
因为这样一切都更可信了
because it gave the whole thing credibility.
给别人一份报纸又要他放在某处
It's not a crime to give someone a piece of paper
不算是犯罪
and have them drop it off at an address.
但是在法庭上撒谎是犯罪
But it is a crime to lie about it under oath,
我会让你出庭作证
and I'm gonna put you on that stand.
你不能强迫我为自己的案子作证
You can't force me to testify in my own case.
恐怕当你质疑哈维品格的时候
I'm afraid you opened the door to that one
就为此打开了渠道
when you made Harvey's character an issue,
因为如果他品格有问题  你也有问题
because if his character's at issue, then why isn't yours?
我没有违反法律
Look, I broke no laws,
我们都知道珍妮特・斯坦格有罪
and we all know that Janet Stanger is guilty.
如果她有罪而你又像自己以为的那样厉害
And if she's guilty and you're as good as you think you are,
你该不用设计这些把戏
you should have gotten her convicted
就让她认罪
without planting that bullshit.
现在呢  安迪
So which is it, Andy:
你想在庭上被羞辱
do you want to be humiliated on the stand,
还是现在放弃这个案子
or do you want to drop this case right now,
你操纵证据的混蛋
you evidence-manufacturing piece of shit?
阿瑟  感谢你即时见我
Arthur, I appreciate you meeting me on such short notice.
我也感谢让别人
And I appreciate the opportunity
跪在我面前的机会
to have somebody grovel at my feet.
我知道我们现在的处境
Look, I know the position we're in.
事实上  法官还没裁定你的动议
The fact is, the judge hasn't ruled on your motion yet, and--
你想要和解
You want a settlement.
我只是想
I'm just talking about something
在我客户面前留住脸面
that allows me to save face with my clients.
我说了  我感谢别人
As I said, I appreciate the opportunity
跪在我面前的机会
to have someone grovel at my feet.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
这是你们要赔偿的金额
That's what you're going to pay us.
这是之前的三倍
This is three times what it was before.
我知道  因为现在你们知道了
I know, because as of now, you've been notified
阿瑟・克特里奇的行为
of Arthur Kitredge's behavior,
意味着下次再有这种情况
which means the next time it happens,
你们都负个人责任
you're all personally liable.
狗改不了吃屎
A man who did this once is gonna do it again.
你混蛋  这行不通
You son of a bitch, this is not gonna work.
不敢苟同  不知道你有没有注意到
Oh, I beg to differ because I don't know if you noticed,
今天只有我来了
but it's just me here today.
那又怎样
So what?
我们在这里的时候  我女儿
So while we're here, my daughter,
那个你认为在董事会面前不敢开口的女人
the woman you wouldn't think could hold her own in a boardroom,
她现在就在你的董事会
she's with your board right now
解释你怎样不值得留任
explaining how you're not worth it anymore.
鉴于你们最近没有出过庭
Because in case you haven't been in a courtroom recently,
大部分陪审团成员不是有钱年长的白人
most juries aren't made up of rich, old white men.
-胡说  -你在吓唬人
- Bullshit. - You're bluffing.
-不是胡说  我们在你之前带着
- It's not bullshit. We got to them before you did
一锤子买卖报价找了他们
with a take-it-or-leave-it offer.
选择在你们
The choice is yours.
你们接受和解  撤职首席执行官
You take the settlement and you remove your CEO...
要么去跟你不一路的陪审团面前碰运气
Or you could roll the dice with a jury not of your peers.
不管怎样  你都完了
Either way, you are done.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, hey, what's going on?
别告诉我马利克想逃掉协议
Don't tell me that Malik tried to weasel out of that agreement.
不是  都很好  我只是想让你顺路过来
No, it's all good. I just wanted to stop by and say
为你一开始拿给我这个案子道声谢
thank you for bringing me this case in the first place.
这意味着我们为监狱的事扯平了吗
Does that mean we're even for the prison thing?
扯平了
We're even.
谢谢  迈克
Thanks, Mike.
哈维
Harvey...
你昨晚后和唐娜谈话了吗
did you talk to Donna since last night?
没  只发短信说我们赢了  怎么了
No, other than to text her we won. Why?
-没什么  -别担心  迈克
- Nothing. - Don't worry, Mike.
我知道她这几天过得很难
I know she's had a rough time.
我会告诉她我们教训了马利克
I'll tell her we stuck it to Malik
而且她功不可没
and we couldn't have done it without her.
我正希望你还在
I was hoping you'd still be here.
你想干什么  亚历克斯
What do you want, Alex?
给你一直想要的东西
To give you what you wanted all along,
我下跪乞求
me on my knees begging.
-继续说  -你赢了  伊莱
- I'm listening. - You won, Eli.
我不能阻止你抢走辉瑞制药
I can't stop you from taking Pfizer,
但这不关乎他们或者汤米・布莱顿什么的
but this wasn't about them or Tommy Bratton or anything else.
而因为我的离开
This was about me leaving,
现在我愿意做任何事
and now I'm asking what it will take
让你远离我的律所
to get you to back off my firm.
那好
Okay, then...
皮-斯可以留着辉瑞制药
Pearson Specter can keep Pfizer,
你只要带着你所有的客户
and all you have to do is come back here
回到这里
with every other client you have.
这才是你一直想要的  不是吗
That's what you wanted all along, isn't it?
你让你的客户找我客户的麻烦  让我陷入
You had your client go after mine to put me in the position
坑哈维的境地
of having to screw Harvey over.
正是
That's right.
那份协议阻止了我挖人
That agreement may have stopped me from poaching,
但总会有别的办法
but there's always a workaround.
所以呢  在那里作为丢了
So which is it, stay there a diminished man
最大客户的弱者
without your best client
还是回到属于你的地方
or come back here where you belong?
告诉你吧  伊莱
You know what, Eli?
我想我会呆在现在的地方
I think I'm gonna stay exactly where I am,
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
at Pearson Specter Litt,
还有我所有的客户
with every damn one of my clients.
-什么  -你刚承认
- Excuse me? - You just admitted
你策划了接管企图
that you orchestrated a takeover attempt
唯一目的就是违反协议
for the sole purpose of breaching our agreement.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
-你算计我  -没错
- You set me up! - That's right.
你抓到我们了  伊莱  现在又丢了
You had us, Eli, and now you don't,
因为如你所说  总有挽回的办法
because like you said, there's always a workaround.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
让你不把它交出去的代价是我欠你一次
The price for you not handing that over is that I owe you one.
瞧瞧现在是谁求饶了
Well, look who's on their knees now.
晚安  伊莱
Good night, Eli.
有需要我会找你
I'll be in touch when I need you.
-成了吗  -大胜
- Did it work? - Like a charm.
感谢上帝  我实在无法
Oh, thank God. I couldn't stand the thought
忍受再次让这里的另一个人失望了
of letting down another person in the office.
路易  我认为
Louis, from what I've seen,
你从来都没让这公司的人失望过
you've never let anyone in this firm down.
我有
Well, I did.
是时候弥补错误了
And it's time I made it right.
你怎么来了  安迪
What are you doing here, Andy?
我来告诉你也许你是赢了官司
I came here to tell you that you may have won the case,
但我还是会报复你的
but I still wanted to get back at you,
所以我打算报复你的导师
so I decided to come after your old mentor.
如果你以为
If you think Cameron Dennis
卡梅隆・丹尼斯解决不了你
can't handle whatever you throw at him,
那你是疯了
you got another thing coming.
我说的不是卡梅隆・丹尼斯
I'm not talking about Cameron Dennis.
我说的是你另一位导师  杰西卡・皮尔逊
I'm talking about your other mentor, Jessica Pearson.
-你干了什么  -不是我
- What did you do? - I didn't do it.
是你  在你让她替你和迈克・罗斯
You did, when you let her take the bullet
挡枪的时候
for you with Mike Ross.
安德鲁  此事只关你我  与她无关
Andrew, this is between you and me, not Jessica.
瞧瞧  现在成安德鲁啦
Wow, look at that. Andrew, huh?
不是马利克也不是安迪了  是安德鲁
Not Malik or Andy, Andrew.
听着  她为迈克・罗斯做的事与你无关
Listen to me, what she did for Mike Ross doesn't involve you.
当然有关  因为她在纽约律师协会面前
Oh, it involves me because she admitted to being a party
承认了她实行了欺诈
to fraud in front of the New York State Bar.
好笑的是  好像没人在乎
Funny thing is, no one seemed to care.
我在乎  所以我提出动议吊销她的执照
Well, I did, so I whipped up a motion to have her disbarred,
这样的动议如果是
and when a motion like that
总检察长的办公室提出的
comes from the Attorney General's Office,
天哪  人要是认真起来真是吓人呢
man, it is amazing how much people start to care.
-你个混蛋  -终于出现了
- You son of a bitch. - Ah, there it is.
我就是为你这个表情来的
That's the look I came here to see.
如果说还有什么能比这个表情更有价值
The only thing better would be if I could be there
那只能是目睹你
when you have to tell Jessica Pearson
亲口告诉她你害她被吊销执照了
that you cost her her license to practice law.
祝你晚上愉快  哈维
Have a nice evening, Harvey.
路易  接电话
Louis, pick up the phone.
这是我第三次来电话了
This is the third time I've called.
我们需要今晚就找到我们认识的所有
We need to get to anyone we know at the New York Bar
在纽约律师协会的人
on the phone tonight.
安德鲁・马利克打算吊销杰西卡的执照
Andrew Malik's trying to have Jessica disbarred.
不是打算  他已经做了
Not trying. He already did.
-杰西卡  -哈维  放下电话
- Jessica. - Harvey, put that phone away.
木已成舟  没有什么挽回余地了
This is happening, and there's nothing we can do about it.
有很大的挽回余地
There's a hell of a lot we can do about it,
我们也必须挽回
and we're going to.
不  不行  听我的
No, we're not. Listen to me.
我们早知道会这样  我说了没关系
We knew this could happen, and I said it doesn't matter
因为芝加哥不在乎
because in Chicago, nobody's going to care.
我才不管芝加哥  我在乎
I don't give a shit about Chicago. I care.
但这不是你的决定
And it's not your decision.
杰西卡  我们墙上不能有一个
Jessica, we can't have a name on the wall
被吊销执照的合伙人的名字
of a partner that's been disbarred.
你以为我是来干什么的
What the hell do you think I'm doing here?
不  我不干
No, I'm not doing it.
你必须干
Yes, you are.
哈维  是时候把我的名字摘下来了
Harvey, it's time to take my name off the wall.
不能像这样摘
Not like this,
我们经历了那么多  不能这么结束
not after all we've been through.
我不在意
I'm good with this,
这也不是我的律所了
and it's not my firm anymore.
是你的
It's yours.
我没准备好
I'm not ready.
早在今年初你就准备好了
You've been ready for the better part of a year,
你也很清楚
and you know it,
所以唯一的问题是
so the only question is,
你是要跟我纠缠
are you going to fight me on this,
还是选择接受
or are you gonna accept it?
如果我选择接受呢
And what if I say I accept it?
那你就得和路易商量了
Then you need to go and talk to Louis
因为你有两个问题需要解决
because you've got two things to figure out:
你打算花多少钱买断我
how much you're gonna spend to buy me out
还有你打算怎么解释这件事
and how are you gonna spin this thing?
唐娜  你有时间吗
Donna, you have a minute?
干什么的时间  路易
A minute for what, Louis?
为了听你说为什么你
So you can tell me how it wasn't your fault
没有为我准备出庭不是你的错吗
that you didn't prepare me to be on the stand?
给我道歉的时间
A minute to say I'm sorry.
你是对的  唐娜
You were right, Donna.
我应该为你准备接受马利克盘问
I should have prepared you for Malik,
但我没有  因为
but I didn't because
我无法接受当着满屋子人的面  质问你
I couldn't bear the thought of asking you about Harvey
和哈维的关系
in front of a room full of people.
路易  我知道你会这么问的
Louis, I knew that would come up.
我能接受
I was ready to handle it.
但我不能  因为希拉
But I wasn't, because of Sheila.
跟希拉有什么关系...
What does Sheila have to do with--
我和她睡了  唐娜
I slept with her, Donna.
我告诉过你  她要结婚了
I told you she was getting married.
当我做问题列表时
When I was writing down questions,
我一直在想象自己的生命被盘问的样子
I kept imagining someone putting my life on trial,
我实在  无法忍受
and I just--I couldn't take it,
所以我当了懦夫
so I took the coward's way out,
我没有为你准备
and I didn't prepare you.
我理解  路易
I understand, Louis,
我接受你的道歉
and I accept your apology.
谢谢  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
路易  怎么了
Louis, what is it?
自从我离开那个房间  我就一直裹足不前
Ever since I left that hotel room, I've been stuck.
我们又在一起了  那感觉和以前一模一样
We were together again, and it felt just like it did before,
只是这次她不属于我了
except it wasn't because she wasn't mine,
从那时起  我就一直在数日子
and since then, I've been counting the days
数我的灵魂伴侣嫁做人妻
until my soul mate marries someone else
永远离开我的生活的日子
and walks out of my life forever.
-路易  -我知道她和别人在一起
- Louis-- - I know she's with another man,
唐娜  我也知道她说她很爱他
Donna, and I know she says that she loves him,
但我真的很想告诉她
but all I want to do is just say to her,
她难道就看不出来  她的真命天子
can't she see the man she was meant to be with
其实就站在她面前吗
is standing right in front of her face?
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我应该在我本来有机会时告诉她
I should have told her when I had the chance,
但那现在成了我这辈子
but that's something I'm gonna have to live with
必须背负的遗憾了
for the rest of my life.
正好  你还在  路易呢
Good, you're still here. Where's Louis?
我有事找他  我觉得你们俩都...
'Cause I have some news, and I think you should both--
对不起  哈维
I'm sorry, Harvey.
我必须弄清楚
I just had to know.